我们在干嘛?
What are we doing?
探索飞马座星系
那就是我们要做的
Exploring the pegasus galaxy, it's what we do.
你知道我的意思
You know what I meant.
这里没有任何东西能
帮我们对抗幽灵族
There certainly doesn't appear to be anything here that would help in our fight against the wraith
或者复制人
or the replicators.
拜托  我真服了你们了
Come on, you guys kill me.
行星是广袤的
这你们应该知道
Planets are huge, you know.
通常都是你在抱怨
Usually you're the one complaining.
对啊  这么热情可真不像你  罗德尼
Yes, this enthusiasm is most unlike you, rodney.
我正在改头换面
Well, I'm turning over a new leaf.
我们在小飞船里做了个
标准的空中飞跃
We did a standard fly-over in the jumper
探测生命迹象  一无所获
scanned for life-signs. Nothing.
你不能只飞10分钟就说
这里什么都没有
You can't fly around for 10 minutes and decide there's nothing here.
是的  我可以
Yes, I can.
我探测到了奇怪的能源
I'm getting strange energy readings.
是吗?  在哪儿?
Yeah? From where?
我无法标记来源
I can't pinpoint the source.
这个丛林太密了
The jungle's pretty thick, though.
它可能藏在任何东西之内
It could be hiding just about anything.
我不知道
I don't know.
就好像某人在温暖舒适的房间里
It's almost as if somebody in a warm cozy room
敲着他们的电脑
typing at their computer
为了自己开心把我们派到这里
sent us here for their own amusement.
你不会真的认为泽兰卡
会那么做吧?
You don't really think zelenka would do that?
如果他做了  他就惨了
If he did, he's going to be sorry.
你知道在古人的数据库里有多少个
星际之门的地址
Do you have any idea how many gate addresses there are in the ancient database
是没有相关描述的
that have no accompanying description?
42个?
42?
不  我想比那更多  瞧  我记不清了
可那不是重点
No, I think it's a little more than that. Look, I don't really remember. That's not the point.
没什么
Nothing
什么信息都没有  我想说
No information at all. I say
那一定意味着什么
that has to mean something.
或许它表示  对于这些星球没什么
有价值的东西可以记录
Maybe it means there was nothing worth writing about on those planets.
或者有
Or there is
只是古人们试图将它藏起来
but the ancients are trying to hide it.
为了他们自己?
From themselves?
古人之后又过了很长时间
A lot of time has passed since the ancients were around.
你应该知道  事情会改变  或许
这里有些他们不知道的事
You know, things change. Maybe there's something here they didn't know about.
你对此下了赌注  对吗?
You have a bet riding on this, don't you?
你为什么这么说?
What makes you say that?
好吧...
All right...
没错
That's it.
我宣布此次行动结束
都回到小飞船上
I'm calling this one. Everyone back to the jumper.
拜托
Aw, come on.
面对现实吧  麦凯  这次你输了
Face it, mckay, you lost this one.
等等  那是什么?
Hello, what's that then, huh?
看起来像某种自然晶体生物
Looks like some kind of natural crystalline growth.
我想或许就是它导致了能量的读取
I think this might be what's causing the energy readings.
真漂亮
Pretty.
看起来像童年时的某种玩具
Looks like one of those toys you play with when you're a kid.
海军准将64?
A commodore 64?
三筒手枪?
Triple barrel shotgun?
万花筒
A kaleidoscope.
你知道这意味着什么吗?
You realize what this means?
我们发现了一株
能发光的外星真菌
We discovered an alien fungus that glows.
不如说是长在树上的能量源?
How about a power source that literally grows on trees?
但必须承认
这些能量读取水平较低
But admittedly, these energy readings are pretty low-level, but
但是如果我们能培养这些水晶  那么
if these crystals could be cultivated, then--
哇  等等  你在干嘛?
whoa, whoa, wait. What are you doing?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
嗯  我没事  只是
Uh, yeah, I'm fine. Just
受了点电击
a little shock.
那可能很危险!  我告诉过你它在
放射能源
That could have been dangerous! I told you it was giving off energy.
老实说  我...
Honestly, I...
我不知道我为什么那么做
I don't know why I did that.
你杀死它了
Well, you killed it.
真的吗?
Oh, really?
它不再放射能源了
Well, it's not giving off energy anymore.
或许他只是吓倒它了
Well, maybe he just scared it.
你甚至都不知道它是否是活的
You don't even know if it was alive.
老实说  你为什么碰它?
Seriously, why would you touch it?
我不知道!  我说过了  行了吗?
I don't know! I said that, okay?
我只是那么做了
I just did.
现在  你能不提这事了吗?
Now, will you leave it at that?
好吧  这附近一定还有更多
Okay, well, there's got to be more of them around here.
我建议派遣一支科学小组来这里
考察
I'm going to recommend sending a science team back here to check it out.
我就是一个科学小组
I am a science team.
嗯  好
Okay, fine,
让我们抛弃一个潜在重要的探索吧
let's desert a potentially significant discovery
就因为你们不想让我赢和
泽兰卡打的赌
just because you guys don't want me to win a bet with zelenka?
你的扫描都没有问题
All your scans are clear
血液检查很正常
blood tests are normal.
据我所知  你很健康
As far as I can tell, you're in perfect health.
看吧?  我告诉过你
See? I told you.
谢谢你  医生
Thanks, doc.
不许再碰奇怪的东西了
No more touching strange things.
嗯  好建议
Well, that's good advice.
不知道你感觉如何  我很困了
I don't know about you, but I'm exhausted.
真是漫长的一天
It's been a long day.
谢谢你陪我过来
Well, thanks for hanging out.
只想确认一下
Just wanted to make sure.
我很好
I'm fine.
睡会儿吧
Get some sleep.
晚安  约翰
Good night, john.
星际之门亚特兰蒂斯
第四季  第四集
Stargate Atlantis
Season 04 Episode 04
这真不错
This is pretty good.
什么?
What is it?
我就知道你们最终会在一起
I knew you two were going to eventually hook up.
我们没在一起
We are not hooking up.
只是晚餐罢了
It's just dinner.
我告诉过你  这里有东西放射出
奇怪的能量
I'm telling you, there's something in here giving off a strange energy reading.
约翰  你在干嘛?
John, what are you doing?
卡特中校不相信你
Colonel carter doesn't trust you.
除了我没人相信你
No one does but me.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你怎么了?
What's wrong with you?
- 你什么意思?
- 没什么
What do you mean? Nothing.
自从你进入那个幽灵王后的思想后
你就变得不一样了
You've never been the same since you got into the mind of that wraith queen.
什么?
What?
泰勒!
Teyla!
父亲?
Father?
我甚至都没法告诉你它有多么诡异
I cannot even begin to tell you how bizarre it was.
- 拜托  你想听诡异的?  让我告诉你
- 知道吗
- Please, you want bizarre? Let me tell you--
- you know what?
不用
Don'T.
早上好
Morning.
怎么了?
What?
泰勒昨晚梦见你了
Teyla had a dream about you last night.
罗德尼
Rodney...
真的吗?
really?
关于什么的?
What was it about?
其实它更像个恶梦
我还是不说的好
Actually, it was more of a nightmare, and I'd rather not talk about it.
我是不是那个冲锋的英雄
将你从怪物手中救出来?
Was i the dashing hero saving you from a big bad monster?
事实上  你就是那个怪物
Actually, you were the big bad monster.
真的吗?
Really?
我说过了  还是不说的好
Like I said, I'd rather not talk about it.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
对不起  我有点头疼
I'm sorry. I have a headache.
昨晚没睡好
I did not sleep well last night.
她真的生我起了?
Is she really mad at me?
我没法控制她梦里的事情
I can't control what's in her dreams.
真的?  你认为你没法控制一个人的梦?
Really? You think you can't control a person's dreams?
我父亲在我七岁时就读白鲸我听
My father read me moby dick when I was seven years old.
我是说  真的  那男的在想什么?
I mean, seriously, what was the man thinking?
你知道我做了多长时间
被鲸鱼吃掉的梦吗?
You have any idea how long I had nightmares about being eaten by a whale?
- 它们没有停止  对吗?
- 没有
- They haven't stopped, have they?
- No.
声音从外面传来
It's coming from outside.
我走向门口  听见跑步声
I go to the opening. I hear darts.
我拉开帐篷  然后
I pull open the tent, and
他进来了
he comes inside.
我知道那不是真正的谢帕德中校
I know it's not really colonel sheppard,
可我不禁觉得他很奇怪
but I can't help but feel different towards him.
你认为是我的潜意识在告诉我
些什么吗?
Do you think it's my subconscious trying to tell me something?
如果你和谢帕德中校之间真的
有什么事
If there is something real going on between you and colonel sheppard
是你认为要说的
that you feel you need to address
那你应该那么做
you definitely should.
否则  别为此困扰
Otherwise, don't let it bother you.
我以前有过十分可怕的恶梦
I've had horrible nightmares before
梦到我小的时候父亲被带走
Of my father being taken when I was a little girl,
然后被猎杀
the cullings since,
但是都没有这种感觉
but none of them have felt like this.
当我醒来时
When I woke up,
几乎喘不过气来
I could barely catch my breath.
我知道这听起来很愚蠢  但
I know it sounds silly, but
我想我害怕睡着
I think I'm actually afraid of falling asleep.
生理上  你一切正常
Well, physically, there's nothing wrong with you.
除了你描述的那些症状
Other than the symptoms you've described,
它们都是由缺乏睡眠引起的
which can all be attributed to lack of sleep.
这个短期内应该会有效
These should help for the short term,
可如果问题持续
but if the problem persists
你一定要再过来
you definitely need to come back
你没法想象睡个安稳觉现在
对我来说有多重要
You have no idea how good the thought of a solid night's sleep makes me feel at this point.
我想我知道
Oh, I think I do.
我不确定自从来到这里后我是否
安稳的睡过
I'm not sure I've had one since I got here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
别客气
Don't mention it.
- 睡个好觉
- 你也是
- Have a good night.
- You too.
凯勒医生  这里有紧急医疗事故
Dr. Keller,  we have a medical emergency.
凯勒医生  请速到医务室来
Dr. Keller, please report  immediately to the infirmary.
怎么回事?
What's wrong?
是泰勒  她有严重的腹腔疼痛
It's teyla. She's in severe abdominal distress.
说你给她开了些药?
Says you gave her some medication?
我给她开了些药帮助睡眠  泰勒?
I prescribed some ambien to help her sleep. Teyla?
她起来吃消夜
Went to the mess for a late-night snack,
她开始抱怨胃痛  然后疼痛就加剧了
she started complaining about her stomach, and then she just doubled over.
我以为你要上床睡觉  你吃了
我给你的药片吗?
I thought you were going to bed. Did you take one of those pills I gave you?
没有
No.
好的  尽量放松  让我看看
Okay, just try to relax. Let me have a look.
抓着她
Hold her for me.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
医生  做点什么
Doctor, do something.
好吧  我们得让她保持镇静  然后
okay, we-we need to sedate her, and, uh--
天啊
Oh, god.
这是真的吗?
Can you believe this?
对不起  医生
Sorry, doc.
没想吓你
Didn't mean to scare you.
我们在装雷达  我不小心划伤了
We were sparring. I got in a lucky shot.
可现在是半夜
It's the middle of the night.
对你来说或许是
Maybe for you.
坐下  让我看看
Sit down, let me have a look.
你需要缝针
You're going to need stitches.
我想我教他太多了
I guess I taught him too much, huh?
嗯  我也这么想
Yeah, I guess so.
知道吗  你不用呆在这儿  我能行
You know, you don't need to stick around. I'm fine.
- 你确定？
- 嗯
- You sure?
- Yeah.
我想明天重赛
I want a rematch tomorrow, though.
嗯  那正是我担心的
Yeah, that's what I was afraid of.
晚安
Good night.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
有事吗?
Something wrong?
嗯?  没有  没事
Hmm? No, nothing.
我想他没和任何人约会  知道吗
I don't think he's seeing anyone, you know--
哦!  不  不
oh! Oh, no. No,
那  那没关系
that'S... that's quite all right.
知道吗  如果你躺下来会更好
You know, this would be easier if you lay down.
好的
Okay.
有人在吗
Hello! Is anyone here?
谁在!
Anyone!
伙计...
Hey, buddy...
你从哪跑出来的
what are you running from?
我也不知道
I don't know.
来
Come on.
抱歉 我...我是不是弄疼你了
I'm really sorry. Did I... did I hurt you?
不 不是
No. No... I'M...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不是故意的...
I didn't mean to...
你睡着了
you fell asleep.
我做了一个很奇怪的梦
I was having the strangest dream.
你真的没事吗
You sure you're okay?
嗯
Yeah.
你继续吧
Go ahead.
我快弄好了
I'm almost done.
这真恐怖
It was terrifying.
有个恶心的外星虫子从你的胃里
爬出来
There you were with this disgusting alien bug crawling out of your stomach
谢帕德上校居然表现得
这好像是他见过最酷的事情
and colonel sheppard was acting like it was the coolest thing he'd ever seen.
听起来跟那部电影一样
That sounds like that movie.
的确  外星人  你看过吗?
Yeah, alien. Have you seen it?
谢帕德上校经常提起这件事
Colonel sheppard speaks of it often.
我还记得我第一次看到它
I still remember the first time I saw it.
我一点都不觉得这很酷
I certainly did not think it was cool.
有一次  在医学院里
One time, in med school,
我居然轻易相信我生物实验课上的
搭档
I made the mistake of confiding to my partner in biology class
结果这成了我这辈子最恐怖的事情
that it had caused my all-time worst nightmares.
他把一条活生生的蛇
He actually planted a live snake
放进我在解剖的尸体里
inside a cadaver I was working on.
我小时候从来没见过
Well, I never saw it as a kid.
我从海报上看到这部电影会很恐怖
I knew from the poster it was going to be too scary.
不对  我那时候16岁
No, I was 16
那时我们附近的剧院举办了一个
恐怖复活节活动
when a neighborhood theater had a horror revival festival.
当时我觉得挺好的
I thought, great, you know,
电影约会  乔瑟琳·罗杰
date movie. So, jocelyn rutger
科学院的三年级学生
third period science
虽然有点古怪  但她有很棒的...
Bit of geek, but she had a great, uh...
算了  你们都知道女生一受惊吓就会
蜷靠在你肩膀上吗
anyway, you know how girls get all scared and curl up on your shoulder?
你们星球上的习俗还真是奇怪
Your planet has some truly strange rituals.
不管怎样  我一紧张就会吃东西
Anyway, I eat when I get nervous.
真的吗
Really?
- 我还真没注意到
- 所以...
- I hadn't noticed.
- Mm... so,
非常紧张  跟着了魔一样工作
very tense, working like a charm.
乔瑟琳在我旁边被吓坏了
我赶紧把花生和爆米花收起来放好
Jocelyn's all freaked out beside me, I'm packing away the goobers and the popcorn
然后那些外星人就从约翰·赫特
身体里冒了出来
and then the alien bursts out of john hurt.
你该不会
You didn'T.
吐了她一身
puked all over her.
我一定得看看这部电影
I have got to see this movie.
你们不觉得奇怪吗
Don't you think it's strange
我们每个人都有过很逼真的噩梦
that each of us has had incredibly vivid nightmares
而且谢帕德中校都出现在我们
梦中的某处
with colonel sheppard being somehow an integral part?
而梦中的谢帕德中校跟他本人
完全不像
Acting most unlike colonel sheppard.
除了我
Not me
你最近做过噩梦吗
Have you had any nightmares recently?
没有一天晚上是不做的
Not a night goes by.
昨晚  我梦到卡特中校邀我去她那
共进晚餐
Last night, I dreamt that colonel carter invited me to her quarters for dinner.
或许你不该告诉我们这些  罗德尼
Maybe you shouldn't be telling us this, rodney.
的确  我说的是噩梦
而不是男人的性幻想
Yeah, I said nightmare, not delusional male fantasy.
你们听我说
Wait and listen.
结果发现她要请我吃柠檬鸡
Turns out she was serving lemon chicken.
我是说  柠檬
I mean, lemon,
而且她请我去的唯一原因是
她要把泽兰卡提升为我的上司
and the only reason she invited me to dinner was to tell me she was promoting zelenka over me.
就这?
That's it?
然后我就被一条鲸鱼给吞了
Then I was eaten by a whale.
别问原因
Don't ask how that happened.
你们都认为我疯了吗?
Okay, do you guys really think I'm crazy?
我明白那只是梦  但是
I realize they're just dreams, but
首先是泰勒  紧接着你来看我之后
我又做了一个
first it was teyla, then right after you came to see me, I had one.
那之后我正好没再做梦了
你给我的药片让我一夜无梦
And that's when mine stopped. Those pills you gave me knocked me out cold.
我给罗恩疗伤时  他也做梦了
And then ronon had one while I worked on him.
这有什么大不了的?
What's the big deal?
就像你说的  这都是噩梦而已
不是吗?
It's like you said, it's just a few bad dreams, right?
或许我真不应该为此事打扰你
I probably shouldn't have bothered you with this.
而且我还没有确凿的证据
I know I don't really have any hard evidence.
相信我  我以前就见过有人把
直觉运用在一些极度疯狂的事情
Well, believe me, I've seen a good hunch go a long way in some pretty crazy circumstances.
尤其是在可疑的情况下
你最好用事实来证明
I'd always rather you were on your toes, especially with anything that seems suspicious.
我知道做点小噩梦不是那么严重
I know a few bad dreams isn't that significant.
这很自然  都是来自我们日常生活
的东西
It's only natural, given what we face on a daily basis, but
这次却不一样
this was different.
确实让我很困扰
It really rattled me.
接二连三地发生
Coupled with the sequential pattern.
首先是泰勒  接着是我
First teyla, then me
然后到罗恩  谢帕德中校都在
我们梦里扮演了一个反面角色
then ronon, all with colonel sheppard being a significant negative presence in our dreams.
你们觉得这说明了什么
Do you have any idea what's behind it?
我不知道
No, I don't know.
我想说的是  这一切都发生在
谢帕德中校在m3x-387碰了那块水晶后
Thing is, it started right after colonel sheppard touched that crystal on m3x-387.
我还以为你已经把他治好了呢
I thought you cleared him medically.
- 我是治好了 但
- 打扰一下
- I did, but--
- excuse me.
飞船人员的宿舍中心有紧急情况
There's an emergency situation at crew quarters atrium.
他们紧急呼叫求援
我们已经派人过去了
Security was called for and has been dispatched.
知道了  抱歉
Thank you. Excuse me.
把枪放下来  中校
Put down the gun, major.
我们好好谈谈
Let's talk this out.
谁把反复制人发生器拿过来  现在
Someone, get an arg. Now.
用那个朝他射击
Shoot him with it.
中校  跟我谈谈
Major, talk to me.
告诉我发生什么事了
Tell me what's going on?
照我说的做!
Just do it!
会  会造成什么伤害吗?
Okay, w-what's the harm?
我是说  如果他是人类的话
就不会伤害到他 对吗?
I mean, if he's human, it won't hurt him, right?
- 约翰  他在说什么呢?
- 别跟他讲话
- John, what is he talking about?
- Don't talk to him.
谢帕德中校是个复制人
Colonel sheppard is a replicator.
罗恩  我不知道你脑子里在想什么
Look, lorne, I don't know what's gotten into you...
我?
me?
不  不  原因不在我
No, no, no, no, it's not me.
中校  先把武器放下怎么样?
Major, how about you lower your weapon?
他是个复制人!
He's a replicator!
你们都不相信我?  那我开枪了
你们看好了
What, you don't believe me? I'll shoot him, you'll see.
你完全没有必要这么做
我手里没武器
that won't be necessary. I've got my hands up
我对你不构成任何威胁
in a very non-threatening way.
我叫人去拿反复制人发生器了
I've called for an arg.
- 你相信他的话?
- 当然不
- You believe him?
- Of course not
但是那对你也不造成伤害
而且能让他把武器放下来
but it won't hurt you, and it might help him to lower his gun.
你跟他是同伙的
You're one of them, too.
你们别光站在那!  冲他们开枪
把他们俩都打死!
Don't just stand there! Shoot them. Shoot both of them!
我拿着这个  没必要对你们俩开枪吧?
I take it I don't have to shoot either of you with this?
真高兴没人受伤
I'm so glad no one was hurt.
你什么都不记得了吗
And you don't remember anything?
不记得了
No.
10岁之后  我就再也没梦游了
I haven't had a sleepwalking  incident since I was, like, 10.
这对有梦游症的人来说很正常
It's quite common for someone suffering from somnambulism
他们在睡眠中会表现复杂的行为
to perform complex activities in their sleep
醒来后就什么都不记得了
and remember nothing upon waking.
所以你们认为
这与我碰过那个水晶有关?
So you think this has something to do with the crystal I touched?
一切都是从那以后开始的
That's when it seemed to start.
罗恩中校并不是第一个
Major lorne's not the only one.
每个案例中  受害者都说你在噩梦面
扮演一个负面的角色
In each case, the person being affected reports you being a significant negative presence in the nightmare.
这又不是我能控制的
Well, I can't control that.
对  可或许某种东西能
No, but maybe something is.
什么?
What?
你认为有人在他们的梦里假扮我?
You think someone's impersonating me in their dreams?
我知道很多外星实体都能这么做
Look, I've seen more than my share of alien entities that are capable of this.
奥尼尔中校有一次被一种以水晶形式
存在的神秘力量所击晕
Colonel o'neill was once knocked unconscious by an energy being that lived in crystal form.
而且那东西一度还变成了他的样子
It took on his appearance for a while.
据我所知  你曾经被一个外星组织
所控制
I read at one point, you were taken over by an alien entity.
对
Yeah.
这不是什么光彩的事情
Not a personal highlight.
问题是  你到底想要说什么?
The question is, what's the point?
或许它以我们的恐惧为能量
Maybe it's feeding on our fear.
我闭嘴好了
I'll shut up.
不  不用  那东西没这么大的能耐
No, no, it's not that big a leap.
只不过...
It's just...
我们没有任何证据
we don't have any proof.
首先是泰勒
First, it was teyla.
接着到我
I was next, and then
罗恩是在我给他治疗后发生的
ronon after I treated him...
我才是那个碰过水晶的人
可我却从来没做过一场噩梦
well, I'm the one who touched the crystal, and I've never had a bad dream.
或许这就是你出现在大家梦里的
原因
Maybe that's why you're appearing in everyone's dreams.
无论是什么在做都冠上你的名义
Whatever's doing this imprinted your image onto itself.
现在我明白了  不管它可能是什么
Now that I think about it, it's possible whatever this is,
它只局限于通过触碰来传播
its spread may be limited by touch.
那好
Okay
谁在事故发生之前与罗恩中校
有过接触  都要被隔离
anyone who's had contact with major lorne since the incident needs to be isolated.
如果这真的与某些外星球影响有关
If this is some sort of alien influence,
我们必须得找到方法来探测它
we have to find a way to detect it.
罗德尼  坐啊
Sit down, rodney.
我这样也不错  谢谢
I'm good right here, thank you.
已经联系上所有飞行在外的队伍
告诉他们暂时不要回来了
All off-world teams have been contacted and instructed not to return for the time being.
如有必要的话 星门的通行得严加限制
Gate travel will be restricted to an as-needed basis,
在接到通知前  所有不必要的
出征队员
and until further notice, all non-essential expedion members
都要求呆在营房中
will be restricted to quarters.
拜托 有必要这么做吗
Come on, is this really necessary?
不过是些噩梦而已  对吧?
It's just a few bad dreams, right?
说真的
The fact is,
我们还不清楚我们要对付的是什么
we don't really know what we're dealing with.
我们身边可能会有一个外星组织
We may have an alien entity on our hands
他们会随意地出现在任何人之间
capable of moving from person to person at will.
目前为止  我们能得知的唯一信息是
他们是怀有一定的恶意的
And so far, the only behavior we have to evaluate suggests a certain malice.
基于大家告诉我的信息
Now, based on what's been described to me,
谢帕德上校出现在大家梦中的形象
the personification of colonel sheppard in everyone's dreams is
都表现得是个不怀好意的人
behaving much like a sociopath.
那我有山羊胡子吗
Did I have a goatee?
目前  它只会让人做噩梦而已
Right now, all it's doing is causing some nightmares
但我们并不知道它到底有多大能耐
but we don't know if that's the limit of its capability.
你的意思是  这只是个开始
You're saying this is only the beginning.
我从没 见过这种事情
I've never profiled anything like this before.
它很可能会慢慢发展
It will likely progress,
并试图把危害扩大  造成大范围的影响
try to drive up the stakes, seek bigger thrills.
现在即使它局限于只能
能操纵一个人的潜在意识
Now, even if it's limited to manipulating the host's subconscious,
它也能对人造成严重的危害
it may be able to put someone in serious jeopardy.
我们到底在讨论什么  鬼王弗兰迪吗?
So, what are we talking, freddy krueger here?
拜托  我们现在连一丁点证据
都没有呢
Oh, come on! We don't have a single shred of hard evidence here.
我是说  就算我们有证据
那也只不过是一个可怕的人而已
I mean, until we do, this thing is just a bogeyman.
这就是为什么你们要回到
Exactly why you're going back to the planet
那个谢帕德上校摸到那块水晶的星球上
where colonel sheppard touched the crystal.
什么
What?
我们为什么要这么做?
Why would we do that?
正如你所说
Well, just as you said,
去收集点确凿的证据
to gather some hard evidence
去看看还有没有类似的东西
see if there are any more of these things.
我们得确切地知道它们是什么
它们又是怎么样运作的
We need to find out exactly what they are, and how they work,
如果可以的话 怎么去预防它
就像现在在罗恩体内那个
and if possible, how to detect if there really is something inside lorne right now.
谢谢
Thank you.
但  但你刚说取消星际飞行
But-but you said no more gate travel.
我认为那个决定很明智
I thought that was a wise decision.
我说过是在需要的基础上  麦凯
I said on an as-needed basis, mckay.
我想这个能行
I think this qualifies.
对  你不认为一个科学小组更合适...
Yeah, but don't you think a science team would be better suited for--
你就是一个科学小组  记得吗?
you are a science team, remember?
好吧  可你应该知道这是个很大的
星球
Okay, fine, but it's a big planet, you know.
我们可以投入更多人力
We could really use some more manpower.
我还是不敢相信你居然真让我
干这个
I still can't believe you're making me do this.
你赌输啦
Ah, you lost the bet.
这星球上一定存在着什么
There's definitely something on this planet.
对  但我很清楚的说过  是"有价值的"
东西
Yes, but I distinctly said "of value."
我可不认为这次探索有价值
I hardly call this particular discovery valuable.
这里
Over here.
就是这儿
There you go.
赶紧开始吧
Better get started.
- 罗德尼
- 什么事?
- Rodney...
- hmm?
别往里看
Don't look in it,
还有  无论你做什么  别碰它
and whatever you do, don't touch it.
我甚至都没在意它
I wasn't even thinking about it.
瑞迪克  这儿有株活的
Radek, we got a live one here.
比较下这两个应该会有帮助
It could be useful to compare the two.
那只是我的想法
That's just what I was thinking.
但是要小心  想摘取一株带有
活动实体的可能很危险
But be careful. It could be dangerous to try to harvest one with an active entity in it.
你又猜对了我的想法  可是
Once again, you've read my mind. However,
在你说完之后  我还是要说
你应该试试
when you're finished there, I say you give it a shot.
对  应该试试
Yeah, give it a shot.
你真认为带一株活的回去是安全的?
You really think it was safe to bring a live one back?
这些容积箱是不具备传导性的
Those containment tanks are non-conductive.
我们认为它需要传导性物质
才能移动
We believe it needs conductive material in order to travel.
而拥有一颗活水晶
And having an active crystal
能让我们校正这些手拿探测器
allows us to calibrate these hand-held sensors
来探测和它相关的能量踪迹
to detect the energy signatures associated with it.
幸运的话  如果某人体内携带了这些
生物  我们就能查出来
Hopefully, we'll be able to determine if someone is carrying one of these creatures inside of them.
只要它不知道我们的目的
As long as it doesn't know what we're up to.
否则  在我们扫描他们之前
它就会从那个人身体里转移出去
Otherwise, you'd think it would just transfer out of somebody before we could scan them.
你的推测是  他们不仅有能力还有
意识  并且随时处在戒备状态
You're assuming they're not only capable, but they're conscious and aware at all times.
它展示了到目前为止极高的智商
It's demonstrated pretty sophisticated intelligence so far.
你认为它有基础防御技能
You think it would have basic avoidance skills.
我们得修正下扫描仪以便在更大的
范围内操作来...
We're going to have to modify our scanners to operate at a range large enough to...
等等
wait a minute
- 我们可以校正城市范围生命迹像监测仪
- 哦  是啊 巫师先生
- we could calibrate the city-wide life-signs detector--
- oh, yes, mr. Wizard,
我们只需要打个响指  然后...
we're just going to snap our fingers and--
你在干嘛?
what are you doing?
我不知道  它...
I don't know, it'S..
它能将人催眠
it's mesmerizing.
你说过它很安全
You said it was safe.
我们说的是我们认为  但是...
We said we think. Still...
我不知道我刚刚做了些什么
I don't know what I was doing.
真难以置信  我突然有种冲动
很想去碰它
I can't believe it. I was suddenly overcome by the compulsion to want to touch it.
嗯  我们认为它就是那样
Yeah, we think that's how it...
捆住受害者的
ropes in its victims.
不在他体内
It's not in him.
你说过实体需要传导性物质才能
移动  对吗?
You said the entity needed conductive material to travel, right?
呃  根据...
Well, based on the...
是能量管
it's the power conduits.
它们几乎遍布整个城市
They run pretty much through the entire city.
它可能在任何人的体内
It could be in anyone.
凯特
Kate,
你在干嘛?
what are you doing?
我不想死
I don't want to die.
很好  从那儿下来
Good. Come down from there.
我不能
I can'T.
为什么不?
Why not?
帮帮我  求你了
Help me, please!
约翰  放开我
John, stop it.
放手  我得帮她
Stop it. I have to help her!
你在干嘛呢?
What are you doing?
约翰  走开!
John, get out of the way!
泰勒!
Teyla!
凯特!
Kate!
她没有出勤  我没法叫醒她
She did not report for duty and I can't wake her up.
她死了
She's dead.
我是卡特中校
This is colonel carter.
各位请注意
If I could have  your attention, please.
我很遗憾的告诉大家  今天我们失去
了探险队里一名十分宝贵的成员
I'm very sorry  to have to tell you  that we have lost  a valuable member  of the expedition today.
凯特·赫特米尔医生对我们所以人来说
都很重要
Dr. Kate heightmeyer meant  a great deal to all of us.
她的死是个巨大的悲剧
Her death  is nothing short of tragic.
同样  我也很遗憾的告诉大家  我们
面临的威胁仍然存在于我们之中
I'm also sorry  to have to report  that the threat we face  is still in our midst,
在进一步通知之前
and until further notice,
全面防范紧闭条款仍然有效
the full lockdown protocol  will remain in effect.
请尽量保持平静
Try to remain calm.
我们正竭尽全力保障大家的安全
We are doing everything we can  to ensure everyone's safety
并尽快解决现状
and to resolve this situation  quickly.
谢谢
Thank you.
那很好
That was good.
我是说
I mean,
当然很可怕
horrible, obviously.
恐怖而且可怕
Terrifying and horrible,
可我只是...
but I just...
我想说你听上去很坚强
I meant you sounded strong.
我肯定听到你的声音  他们至少会
感到一丝安慰
I'm sure they were at least a little reassured hearing your voice
当然你不需要我告诉你这些
but you don't need me to tell you that.
像今天这样  没关系
A day like this, it doesn't hurt.
谢谢
Thanks
我正准备来看你  可是
I was just about to come to see you, but
我不确定你是否想见我
I wasn't sure if you wanted to see me.
卡特中校?  打扰下
Uh, colonel carter? Excuse me.
我想我能够校正城市范围监测仪
I think I've managed to calibrate the city-wide sensors.
我是说  如果它能正常工作
I mean, if it is working properly.
我们有些麻烦...
We had some trouble with the...
我们检测到了一个
we have a positive reading.
知道是谁吗?
Do we know who that is?
你找我干嘛?
What do you need me for?
橡胶墙怎么回事?
What's with the rubber walls?
很抱歉  罗德尼
I'm sorry, rodney.
我必须走了
I have to go.
你在开玩笑吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding.
在罗德尼体内?
It's in rodney?
隔离室被绝缘材料包围着
The isolation room has been lined with insulating material
以防实体从他身上转移到其他人
体内
to prevent the entity from transferring out of him and into someone else.
如果我们没错
If we're right,
我们将它困住了
we've got it trapped.
是啊  可那帮不了麦凯  对吗?
Yeah, well, that doesn't help mckay much, does it?
如果这玩意在梦中将人至于死地
If this thing kills people in their sleep...
我们得想办法让它从他体内出来
we've got to find a way to get it out of him.
有人给我杯咖啡吗?  我已经觉得有点
困了
Someone want to  get me some coffee?  I'm already feeling  a little tired here.
我能给他点东西让他暂时保持清醒
I could give him something to keep him awake for a while, but
可它只能坚持一小会儿  在那之后
他将会有肺衰竭的危险
it will only work for so long before we start putting him at risk of pulmonary failure.
相信我  我很了解
Yeah, believe it or not, I've been there before, too.
你尽力吧
Do what you can.
我们会想到办法的
We'll try to come up with something.
坚持住  麦凯!
Hang in there, mckay!
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
好像我有很多选择似的
Like I have much choice.
你觉得它知道自己被困住了吗?
Do you think it knows it's trapped?
我不知道  怎么了?
I don't know, why?
或许有个办法...
Maybe there's a way to...
我不知道  和它理论
I don't know, reason with it.
呆在韦尔博士的旧办公室里让你
想到了这个  对吗?
Being in dr. Weir's old office made you think of that, didn't it?
通常我直接朝坏蛋开枪
Normally I just shoot the bad guys.
我们刚听说了
We just heard.
一定有我们能帮忙的
There must to be something we can do.
我们正在讨论这个
That's what we're talking about.
好吧  就算你能和它沟通
Okay, let's say for a second that you could somehow communicate with it.
你打算说些什么呢?
What were you planning on saying?
我不知道  我还没想到那里
I don't know, I hadn't gotten that far.
我害怕如果它靠恐惧生存  或者更糟...
It strikes me that if it feeds on fear, or worse,
比如杀死寄主的刺激感  那么...
likes the thrill of killing its host, then...
它就会抓住最后的机会
well, it would take the last chance it had.
杀死麦凯
To kill mckay.
那生存呢?
What about survival?
它被困住了
It's trapped.
如果没有一个活的寄主供它转移
它会死吗?
Will it die without a living host to transfer to?
我可不希望找到答案
I was hoping not to find out.
我们可以给它一个离开的机会
We could give it a chance to leave.
回家
Go home.
- 回到水晶里
- 对  当然  为什么不呢?
- Back into the crystal.
- Yeah, sure, why not?
让它通过星际之门回到自己的
星球上
Send it through the gate back to its planet.
我以前听说过人们能够在梦里
清醒的交谈
I have heard of people being talked through waking dreams before.
或许
Maybe...
或许麦凯能够被催眠
maybe mckay can be hypnotized into
进入一种能和它交谈的状态
a state where he could somehow communicate with it.
他曾成功地通过冥想进入一种
转换的状态
He has successfully meditated into an altered state before.
对  那是在他被基因转化了之后
Yeah, that was after he was genetically altered.
对不起  什么?
I'm sorry, what?
你们想让麦凯叫这玩意离开?
You want mckay to ask this thing to leave?
我们在谈论麦凯
We are talking about mckay.
可怕的并不只是他的力量
Scary things are not exactly his strength
他还面对着一个明显能操控他
潜意识的生物
And he is up against a creature apparently capable of manipulating his subconscious.
我希望能有办法让我们中一人进去
I wish there was a way for one of us to get in there.
进入麦凯的梦中?
Into mckay's dreams?
对
Yeah, you know,
帮助他  给他一些精神上的支持
help him out, give him a little moral support.
拜托
Come on
你见多识广  难道没遇到一种能让人
进入其他人梦境的办法吗?
all the things you've seen, you've never come across a way for one person to get into another person's dreams?
她去哪儿?
Where's she going?
怎么回事?
What's going on?
我不知道  但我觉得
I don't know, but I think
我就快要看到麦凯不为人知的
一面了
I'm about to see a side of mckay I never wanted to see.
不一定非是你不可
It does not have to be you.
当然  是我出的馊注意
Yeah, well, it's my bad idea.
是什么?
What was?
那个...
What...
十年前我们首次碰到这种技术
we first encountered the technology 10 years ago
在一个星球上  那里大屠杀的幸存者
on a planet where the survivors of a holocaust
完全生活在他们意识里的虚拟
世界里
were living entirely in a virtual world created in their minds.
从那以后  我们能修正并将它用于
星际小组成员的虚拟现实训练中
Since then, we've managed to modify it for use in the vr training of sg team members.
只需要一些轻微的校正就能将它
转入潜意识活跃状态
It only took some minor calibrations to tune it in to subconscious activity.
那么谢帕德会看见麦凯的梦?
So sheppard is actually going to see mckay's dreams?
老实说  我们没有检测技术在这方面
的作用
Well, to be honest, the technology is untested for use in this manner.
梦境比有意识的思维更随意
Dreams are much more random than conscious thought.
系统或许很难传达麦凯脑子里的
想法
It may be difficult for the system to translate what's going on in mckay's brain
使谢帕德中校理解
so that colonel sheppard can understand it.
我只希望他们两能够有办法互动
I'm just hoping that the two of them will be able to interact somehow.
你确定吗?
You sure about this?
不确定
Not really.
我有点糊涂了
I'm pretty screwed up.
我知道
You're telling me.
你准备好了我们就开始
We're ready if you are.
谢谢
Thanks.
我什么都没做呢
I haven't done anything yet
谢谢你的尝试
For trying
还有别说我没警告过你
and don't say I didn't warn you.
注入镇静剂
Administering sedative.
什么都没发生
Nothing's happening here.
他还没开始做梦
He's not dreaming yet.
哦  天啊
Oh, boy.
好鲸鱼
Nice whale.
乖鲸鱼  你是我的朋友
Nice whale, you're my friend.
你不想吃我
You don't want to eat me.
放弃吧
Give up.
你不会成功的
You'll never make it.
你太弱小了
You're too weak.
谢谢  谢谢你的鼓励  帮帮我
Oh, thank you. Thanks for the encouragement. Way to help out.
我为什么要帮你?
Why would I want to help you?
因为我以为
Because I thought you--
那不是我  罗德尼
that's not me, rodney.
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
你真可悲
You're pathetic.
你也会被卷进来
You might as well jump in.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
哦  上帝啊
Oh, god,
我得回去  我得回去
那是我唯一的机会
I have to get back. I have to get back. It's my only chance.
你会死在这儿
You're going to die out here.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
别听他的  罗德尼
Don't listen to him, rodney.
你说的轻松!
你为什么不帮我划船?
That's easy for you to say! Why don't you help me row?
知道吗  这比我想象的更奇怪
You know, this really isn't as strange as you lead me to believe.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
那个怎么样?
What about that?
我讨厌小丑
I hate clowns.
你们可以尽情的划
You can paddle all you want.
可你们哪儿都去不了
You're not going anywhere.
他说的对  我们会死在这儿
He's right! I'm going to die out here!
他想让你害怕  别让他得逞
He wants you to be afraid. Don't give him what he wants!
他不能真的伤害你
He can't really hurt you.
那你就错了
That's where you're wrong.
出什么事了?
What happened?
准备
Clear.
他心脏停搏
He's in cardiac arrest.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我已经尽力了
I've done all I can.
他死了
He's dead.
这都是你的错  约翰
This is all your fault, john.
如果你没碰那个该死的石头
麦凯现在还活着
If you hadn't touched that stupid rock, mckay would still be alive right now.
我以为你会帮助他
I thought you were going to help him.
我试了
I tried.
你真够朋友
Some friend you are.
中校  妥协吧
Colonel, you've been compromised.
我决定将你离职
I'm relieving you of duty.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
没事了  没事了
Oh, it's okay. It's okay.
尽量放松
Just try to relax.
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
你刚刚心脏停搏了
You were in cardiac arrest.
那个实体
The entity...
它在谢帕德中校体内
it's in colonel sheppard.
你现在可以放弃
You can quit now.
我不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
哦  是的  你怕
Oh, yes, you are.
我是你唯一害怕的
I'm the one thing you are afraid of.
你让你的朋友失望了
You failed your friends.
你给他们带来灾难
You brought this on them
却没有办法阻止它!
and there is nothing you can do to stop it!
他的心率很高  这很危险
His heart rate is dangerously high.
你能叫醒他吗?
Can you wake him up?
我可以试试  可是以他的身体状况
事情可能变得更糟
I could try, but in his physical state, that could make things worse.
而且实体仍将在他体内
Yes, and the entity would still be in him.
把我和他再连接起来
Hook me up to him again.
起来
Get up.
来啊  约翰
Come on, john.
打啊!
Fight!
不
No.
那正是你想要得
That's what you want.
赫特米尔的死都是你的错
It's your fault heightmeyer's dead.
麦凯的死也是你的错!
Your fault mckay is dead!
我没死
I'm not dead.
你赢不了
You can't win.
是的  我们可以
Yes, we can.
你害怕电击  所以我还活着
You're vulnerable to electric shock. That's why I'm still alive.
你在完成工作之前就离开了
You left before you could finish the job!
这到底怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
你是哪一个?
Which one are you?
是我
Me.
好的你还是坏的你?
Good you or bad you?
是我  是我
Me me.
是真的你吗?
Is that... you you?
我想是
I think so.
谢谢
Thanks.
好吧  这真太奇怪了
Okay, this is really weird.
我知道
You're telling me.
我还以为会有很多...辣妹呢
I thought there'd be more... hot girls
是啊
Yeah
我有个主意
Hey I have an idea.
我们离开这儿如何?
How about we get out of here?
听起来不错
Sounds like a plan.
睡不着
Couldn't sleep.
嗯  我也是
Yeah, me too.
- 尽管我之前吃了些零食...
- 嗯  我们都睡不着
Thought I'd have a little snack before I... yeah, we couldn't sleep either.